Guide to the Walter Lowenfels Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Walter Lowenfels papers
1897-1979
1930-1976
YCAL MSS 367
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
85.51
(183 boxes)
The Walter Lowenfels Papers document the life and work of the writer, journalist, editor, activist, and member of the Communist Party USA, Walter Lowenfels. The papers consist of correspondence, writings, writings of others, photographs, personal papers, printed material, and other papers spanning the years 1897-1979, with the bulk of the material dating from 1930-1976. Correspondence, writings, and writings of others comprise the bulk of the papers. The correspondence records his personal and professional relationships and chronicles his 1953 and 1954 trials for sedition and conspiracy and his publication process. Writings document Lowenfels's work as a writer, editor and anthologist, including drafts of his prose, poetry, drama, essays, and articles. The writings also document his work for the Pennsylvania edition of the Daily Worker. The writings of others reveal Lowenfels's work editing anthologies and collections of works by other writers. Photographs include snapshots of Lowenfels, his family and friends, his home and other subjects. Printed material contains clippings, tearsheets, ephemera, and other printed material concerning Lowenfels and other subjects of his interest. A small amount of personal papers includes biographical information and files on his finances and estate.
Lowenfels, Walter, 1897-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Manna Lowenfels Perpelitt, 1984.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 181-183: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Printed material received with the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
Biographical Note
Walter Lowenfels was born on May 10, 1897 in New York City. His family owned the successful butter manufacturing business Hotel Bar Butter, which provided a comfortable upbringing for Lowenfels. After graduating from preparatory school in 1914, he served in the military during World War I. Following his service, Lowenfels worked for his family's company and wrote poetry, an interest he developed while in the military. Some early poems appeared in local newspapers and in 1925 he published his first collection of poems, Episodes & Epistles. In 1924 Lowenfels met Lillian Apotheker, who co-funded Episodes & Epistles, and moved to Europe with her after he decided to focus on writing and quit the family business. They married in 1926 in Europe. The couple spent time in Florence and settled in Paris, meeting many influential writers, including Henry Miller, T.S. Eliot and Ford Madox Ford, and for a brief time lived with composer George Antheil. Lowenfels's writing was well received and he appeared in journals and little magazines, such as transition and This Quarter. Nancy Cunard admired his poetry and in 1930 published his collection Appolinaire: An Elegy, through her Hours Press. In 1931, he shared This Quarter's Richard Aldington Poetry Prize with e.e. cummings.
While in Paris, Lowenfels met writer Michael Fraenkel. Fraenkel and Lowenfels became close friends and in 1930 co-founded the Carrefour Press. That same year, they published the pamphlet Anonymous: The Need for Anonymity, a manifesto that demanded total anonymity in art and in turn started the "anonymous movement." Lowenfels anonymously published through Carrefour a musical play, U SA with Music: An Operatic Tragedy. The play's anonymity was short-lived since he and Fraenkel were forced to reveal authorship in a 1932 plagiarism suit against composer George Gershwin for his musical Of Thee I Sing. Carrefour lost the case and began to identify published authors, thereby ending the anonymous movement. Lowenfels continued to write poetry and began to edit poetry of others. His interest in politics increased and his poetry began to feature his leftist political ideas, focusing on the rise of fascism in Germany and Italy. The Lowenfels' first three daughters were born in France, Michal and twins Manna and Judy.
Lowenfels and his family returned to the United States in 1934, moving to Mays Landing, New Jersey. Lowenfels returned to his father's butter business and worked alongside his brother, Albert. During that time, Lowenfels introduced new ideas to the business; he invented a new waxed paper packaging for butter and he applied date stamping to improve the butter's freshness. At night and on the weekends, he continued to write poetry. In 1937, he published Steel 1937, a collection of poetry commemorating the steelworkers killed by US Steel during the 1937 Little Steel strike. Following the publication, Lowenfels quit writing poetry. In 1938, he left the family business again and moved to Philadelphia where he began writing for the Pennsylvania edition of the Daily Worker and became increasingly involved in the Civil Rights and Communist movements. He soon became editor and held that job through 1954. His social activism and writing focused on civil and worker's rights. Through the 1940s, he sometimes worked only part-time for the paper, while also selling intercommunication devices and relying on his wife's teaching salary. The couple's family grew to four daughters. In 1951, Lowenfels suffered a heart attack and recovered fully. The same year, his family moved to a cabin in Weymouth, New Jersey.
In July of 1953, Lowenfels was arrested with eight others (they were known as "The Philadelphia Nine") and accused of sedition and conspiracy to overthrow the United States government under the Smith Act. While planning how they could best strategize their defense, the group agreed that Lowenfels should return to writing poetry to raise money. After seventeen years, Lowenfels began to write poetry again and started to translate others' poetry from French and Italian into English. The group was convicted but the government's case was overturned in August of 1953. He was arrested again in 1954 for distributing "subversive" materials and was imprisoned at the Holmsburg County Prison in Philadelphia for treason. His conviction was overturned for lack of evidence in 1954. That same year, he published A Prisoner's Poems for Amnesty. In the midst of Lowenfels's arrests and trial, Lillian was asked to sign a loyalty oath. She pled the Fifth Amendment and was fired from her teaching job. After his release from prison, Lowenfels quit the Daily Worker and devoted himself to writing and editing the writing of others.
Through the 1950s and 1960s, he worked prolifically as an anthologist, focusing on writings that reflected Marxism and opposition to political repression. He published an anthology of Walt Whitman's poetry called Walt Whitman's Civil War (1961); Where Is Vietnam? (1967), a collection of protest poetry for which he is perhaps best known; and In the Time of Revolution (1969), a collection of civil rights poems by African Americans. He was active in the anti-Vietnam War peace movement and edited the anti-war publication Dialog. To protest the war, Lowenfels joined with other writers and editors and refused to pay taxes. An anthology of Lowenfels's own poems edited by Robert Gover, The Portable Walter, was published in 1968, and included the second half of his autobiography My Many Lives. In 1970, Lowenfels co-wrote The Life of Fraenkel's Death with Howard McCord and continued to edit poetry anthologies, publishing several collections, including From the Belly of the Shark: a new anthology of Native Americans; poems by Chicanos, Eskimos, Hawaiians, Indians, Puerto Ricans in the U.S.A., with related poems by others (1973); and For Neruda, For Chile: an international anthology (1975).
Lowenfels died on July 8, 1976 in Tarrytown, New York.
Scope and Contents
The Walter Lowenfels Papers document the life and work of the writer, journalist, editor, activist, and member of the Communist Party USA, Walter Lowenfels. The papers consist of correspondence, writings, writings of others, photographs, personal papers, printed material, and other papers spanning the years 1897-1979, with the bulk of the material dating from 1930-1976.
Correspondence, writings, and writings of others comprise the bulk of the papers. The correspondence records his personal and professional relationships and chronicles his 1953 and 1954 trials for sedition and conspiracy and his publication process. Writings document Lowenfels's work as a writer, editor and anthologist, and include drafts of his prose, poetry, drama, essays, and articles. The writings also document his work for the Pennsylvania edition of the Daily Worker. The writings of others reveal Lowenfel's work editing anthologies and collections of works by other writers.
Photographs include snapshots of Lowenfels, his family and friends, his home and other subjects. Printed material contains clippings, tearsheets, ephemera, and other printed material on Lowenfels and other subjects of his interest. A small amount of personal papers includes biographical information and files on his finances and estate.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1920-1979. II. Writings, 1926-1976. III. Writings of Others, 1941-1976. IV. Photographs, 1897-1975. V. Other Papers, 1931-1976. VI. Printed Material, 1925-1976.
Authors, American -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Civil rights -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Journalists, American -- 20th Century; Protest movements -- United States -- 20th Century; Communism -- 20th Century; Political persecution -- United States -- 20th Century; Protest literature; Social movements -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors; Journalists; Poets; Editors; Journalists; Lowenfels, Walter, 1897-1976
- Correspondence, 1920-1979; Series I; 21; (50 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. is organized into three subseries: General Correspondence, Correspondence by Subject, and Third-Party Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  General Correspondence contains incoming letters to Lowenfels and carbon copies of his outgoing letters. The series documents his career as a poet, editor, and anthologist as well as his personal relationships with family, friends, and colleagues. Some letters include enclosures of poems and writings of others sent to Lowenfels and are noted when they occur. A significant portion of the correspondence is identified by first name only and a smaller amount of correspondence remains unidentified. Included within general correspondence are letters from literary figures such as Henry Miller, Langston Hughes, Gwendolyn Brooks, Nancy Cunard, and Lawrence Ferlinghetti, and musicians and composers such as George Antheil, Pete Seeger, Lee Hays, and Woody Guthrie.
  Correspondence by Subject contains correspondence regarding specific topics or incidents grouped together by Lowenfels. Included in the subseries are files of correspondence relating to Lowenfels's 1953 and 1954 trials for sedition and plotting to overthrow the government. This correspondence includes incoming and outgoing correspondence with Lowenfels, letters from Lillian Lowenfels, and copies of letters written by third parties to Judge Cullen Ganey, President Dwight Eisenhower, and others in support of amnesty for Lowenfels.
  Third-Party Correspondence contains correspondence between other parties, including members of Walter Lowenfels's family and correspondence regarding his estate and posthumous publications, as well as the incoming and outgoing correspondence of his wife Lillian Lowenfels.
  Additional correspondence is located in Series II. Writings and Series III. Writings of Others.
  - General Correspondence, 1925-1976
    This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Correspondence identified by first name only and unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "A" General, 1954-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbe, George, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abelord-Schuman Limited, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Abt, John J., 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ackerson, John, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ackley, Randall, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Addison, Lloyd, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Adnan, Etel, 1967-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Advance Printing Co., 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      General note
      Includes letters from Joel Rothman.
    - Aldan, Daisy, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aldington, Richard, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alexan, George, 1964, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Angoff, Charles, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
      - Cameron, Angus, 1956-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - All Points of View, 1963-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Includes letters from John Stanford.
    - Allen, Samuel, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - American Dialog
      - Frieder, Jacquie, 1965-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
      - To "Friends" from WL, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Moroze, Lewis M., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - North, Joe, 1964-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
      - Vroboská, Anća, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - General, 1964-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - American Literary Exchange, 1963-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Includes letters from Jack Lewis.
    - American Society of African Culture, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - American Weave, 1958-1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Ammons, A. R. (Archie), 1964-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Anderson, Chester, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Includes poems by Anderson.
    - André, Michael, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Antheil, George, 1928-1932, undated (Box 2, Folder 34-36)
    - Appercelle, Andrée, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Letters in French.
    - Aptheker, Herbert, 1962-1976 (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
      American Institute for Marxist Studies, Political Affairs.
    - Arkin, Frieda, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Arnold, Bob, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Arobateau, Red, 1969, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Arts and the People, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      Includes letters by Henri Percikow.
    - Arts In Society, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Includes letters by Monika Jensen.
    - Asselineau, Roger, 1961-1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Atheneum (New York, N.Y.), 1963-1972 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - The Authors Guild, 1955-1971 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Ayling, Ronald, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "B" General, circa 1954-1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 49-51)
    - Babeuf, Howard, 1967, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Bair, Deirdre, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Baraka, Imamu Amiri
      Related Archival Materials note
      See Jones, Leroi, Box 17, Folder 343
    - Barlenmir House, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Barry, Jan, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Bart, Connie, 1955-1968 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Bart, Philip, 1967-1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Bartlett, Elizabeth, 1964-1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Includes first edition volume of It Takes Practice Not To Die, by Bartlett.
    - Bartlett, Paul, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Bates, Scott, 1956-1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Baxandall, Lee, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Baxandall, Rosalyn, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Beacon Press, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Bean, Adelaide, 1962-1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Beaudoin, Kenneth Lawrence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Beckett, Samuel, 1932, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Beecher, John, 1958-1970 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Beissel, Henry, 1965, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Benkovitz, Miriam, 1954-1973 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Bentley, Eric, 1964-1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Bergé, Carol, 1965-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Berger, Art, 1963-1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Berger, Dorothy, 1962-1975 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Bernard, Sidney, 1967-1975 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Bilicke, Tom, 1971-1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Blackburn, Paul, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Blau, Eric, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Blazek, Douglas, 1964-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Blodgett, Harold William, 1962-1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Blue Cloud Abbey (Marvin, S.D.), 1971-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Includes letters by Brother Benét.
    - Blumenthal, Daniel, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Bly, Robert, 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - The Book Review, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      Includes letters by Jay Bail.
    - Bovingdon, John and Bess, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1932-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Brand, Millen, 1955-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 87-93)
    - Bratt, George, 1961-1975 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Braun, Henry, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Braymer, Nan, 1932-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 96-102)
    - Breman, Paul, 1963-1975 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Britt, Alan, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Brittain, Roger, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Broadside Magazine, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Includes letters by Sis Cunningham.
    - Brooks, Edwin, 1967-1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 107-108)
    - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Brown, Bob, 1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Brown, Fred, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Brown University, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Buchman, Marion, 1962-1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Buechel, Paul, 1963-1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Burgum, Edwin Berry, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 115-116)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Burrows, Vinie, 1966-1975 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "C" General, 1950-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 119-122)
    - Cabral, Olga, 1952-1970, undated (Box 7, Folder 123-126)
    - Caffee, Valorie, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Callahan, James D., 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Camus, Albert, 1958 April 29 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Cantu, Martin, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Capek, Abe, 1956, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Cardona-Hine, Alvaro, 1965 September 1 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Cardoza y Aragón, Luis, 1954-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Carrington, Glenn, 1961-1967, undated (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Carrington, Harold, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Case, Clifford P. (Clifford Philip), 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Caspe, Marie, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Cavell, Marcia, 1964 -1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Center for Marxist Education, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Chakovskii, Aleksandr, 1956 - 1972 (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - Charters, Ann, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Childress, William, 1966-1974 (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Chinese Writers' Union, 1954-1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 144)
      Includes letters from Chen Ping-Yi.
    - Chomsky, Noam, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Chute, Robert, 1964, 1967, undated (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Citadel Press, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Clodd, Alan, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Colombo, John, 1968-1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America, 1958-1975 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Congdon, Kirby, 1964-1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 151-152)
    - Connellan, Leo, 1960-1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Continuum Books, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Corinth Books, 1964, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 155)
      Includes letters from Elias and Theodore Wilentz.
    - Corrington, John William, 1962-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Costley, William, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Council on Interracial Books for Children, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 158)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1963-1970, undated (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Cressman, William, 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 160)
    - Crews, Judson, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Crown Publishers, 1961-1976 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1954-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 163-164)
    - Curtis, Norman, 1957-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - "D" General, 1954-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 166-167)
    - Daily World (New York, N.Y.), 1968-1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Dane, Barbara, 1967-1972, undated (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Dangulov, Savva, 1959-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Darcy, Emma and Sam, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Davidson, Richard, 1957-1970 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Davis, Benjamin, 1953-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Davis, George, circa 1931 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Davis, Ossie and Ruby Dee, 1964-1975 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Dawson, Chester S., 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Decker, Clarence Raymond, 1959-1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 177)
      Literary Review
    - Degnan, June Oppen, 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Delacorte Books, 1969-1973, undated (Box 10, Folder 179)
      Gross, Nancy
    - Dell Publishing Company, 1963-1974 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - De Loach, Allen, 1965-1975, undated (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Dennis, R. M., 1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Deutscher Schriftsteller-Verband, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Dial Press, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Dialog House, undated (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Dick, Kenneth C., 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - DiPalma, Ray, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Di Prima, Diane, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Diskin, Bernice, 1957-1974, undated (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - Divĭs, Ivan, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Dobzynski, Charles, 1955-1975, undated (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - Dolsen, James H., 1953-1965 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - Doubleday and Company, inc.
      - Deming, Lynn, 1966-1972 (Box 10, Folder 193)
      - Drymalski, Paul, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 194)
      - Kaufman, Sybil, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 195)
      - McHargue, Georgess, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 196)
      - Polushkin, Maria, 1970-1971, undated (Box 10, Folder 197)
      - Strachan, William, 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 198)
      - Thompson, Janice, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 199)
      - General, 1964-1974, undated (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - Dowden, George, 1966-1973 (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Draper, Muriel, 1922-1934 (Box 10, Folder 202)
      Typescript copies and photocopies of correspondence.
    - Dukess, Murray, 1965, 1975, undated (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Durem, Ray and Dorothy, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - "E" General, 1948-1973 (Box 11, Folder 205)
    - Editions Seghers, 1955, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 206)
    - Eichorn, Douglas, 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 207)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1955, undated (Box 11, Folder 208)
      Photocopies of correspondence.
    - Eliade, Mircea, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - Europa, 1965-1969 (Box 11, Folder 210)
    - Evans, Mari, 1962-1970, undated (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - "F" General, 1954-1975 (Box 11, Folder 212-213)
    - Fabre, Michel, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - Fahey, Harriet, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - Fahnestock, Karol, 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Falk, Richard, 1966-1970 (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Fast, Howard, 1952-1957, undated (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Feinberg, Charles E., 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 219-220)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1957-1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Fine, Albert, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Finklestein, Sid, 1965-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Fishman, George, 1961, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1932 (Box 11, Folder 225)